Guide to the Stanford News Service Audiovisual Recordings SC1125
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Videorecordings, 1936-2011; Series 2
  - Packard Electrical Engineering Building, B-Roll, 8/21/2002; 02-0821-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 2:15:00
    Editing by Delana Lindsey Exterior / interior shots of the building; hummingbird and the fountain
  - Stanford Technology Town Hall meeting, Eric Benhamou, Donald Evans, James Morgan, John Hennessy, 08/27/2002; 02-0827-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 47:00:00
    President John Hennessy moderated a panel on technology and the economy on Tuesday, Aug. 27, in the Gates Computer Sciences Building. The panelists included Eric Benhamou, chairman and CEO of Palm, Inc.; Don Evans, U.S. commerce secretary; and James Morgan, chairman and CEO of Applied Materials. Field Tape Shot-list: Donald Evan ( Sec. of Commence) --Great Tax Cuts; --Internet; --Bandwidth; --Economy; Leroy Hendrix from medical center 4:30:00 --Internet and Medical; James Morgan CEO Applied Materials 35:57:00 --Never thought the internet would be a factor of the economy; Eric Benamou CEO Palm 38:50:00 --Making better investments in bandwidth; --More guidance will help the economy recover from the recession
  - Stanford Technology Town Hall meeting, Eric Benhamou, Donald Evans, James Morgan, John Hennessy, 08/27/2002; 02-0827-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    President John Hennessy moderated a panel on technology and the economy on Tuesday, Aug. 27, in the Gates Computer Sciences Building. The panelists included Eric Benhamou, chairman and CEO of Palm, Inc.; Don Evans, U.S. commerce secretary; and James Morgan, chairman and CEO of Applied Materials.
  - Stanford Technology Town Hall meeting, Eric Benhamou, Donald Evans, James Morgan, John Hennessy, 08/27/2002; 02-0827-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    President John Hennessy moderated a panel on technology and the economy on Tuesday, Aug. 27, in the Gates Computer Sciences Building. The panelists included Eric Benhamou, chairman and CEO of Palm, Inc.; Don Evans, U.S. commerce secretary; and James Morgan, chairman and CEO of Applied Materials. [Material is from a different angle than previous tapes.]
  - SLAC, BaBar, Tunnel and Internal Components, 09/04/2002; 02-0904-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    At the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center (SLAC), Electrons and positrons collide inside a sophisticated, 1,200-ton particle detector called BABAR to create short-lived subatomic particles whose disintegration reveals subtle differences between matter and antimatter. Shots of internal components.
  - Gates Building, Fountain, 09/5/2002; 02-0905-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Fountain with reflection of gates (opening shot) Sign and student enter ing the building 1:34; Fountain wide shot from Gates 4:25; Fountain med shot from Gates 4:58; Fountain tight shot from Gates 5:20; Low view of the fountain 5:44; Overflow of the fountain 6:16 ( medium ); Overflow of the fountain 6:50 ( tight ); Hoover Fountain 7:10
  - David Packard Engineering & William Gates Buildings, 09/09/2002; 02-0909-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Wide shot of Packard and sequoia Long shot of Hoover fountain 00:54:00; Tight shot of Packard 2:41; Packard and fountain 2:01; Sequoia 3:08
  - WTC Remembrance, Rolling Requiem, Mozart's Requiem, 09/11/2002; 02-0911-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:35:00
    On Wednesday morning, a year after American Airlines Flight 11 crashed into the North Tower of the World Trade Center, Schola Cantorum, a more-than-100-member volunteer chorus based in Mountain View, led a community sing-along of Mozart's Requiem at Memorial Church.
  - WTC Bombing Remembrance, Hennessy Speech, 09/11/2002; 02-0911-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    During a remembrance service on Stanford's Main Quad to commemorate the one-year anniversary of the Sept. 11 attacks, President John Hennessy urged those in attendance to "renew our commitment to the enduring ideals for which this country and our university stand." African Chant 5:45; Hindu chant; Lady sings 9:11; Guy sings 12:36; Horn 16:10; Hennessy 16:45
  - Laura Wilson, Chief of Police, Swearing-in, 09/18/2002; 02-0918-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Lt. Laura Wilson is sworn in as chief of police for the Department of Public Safety after former chief, Marvin Moore died unexpectedly of a heart attack in February. Cut Piece; Laura Wilson being sworn into Chief of Police 31:26; Laura gets her badge 33:09; Laura's speech 34:30
  - 2002 Convocation, 09/19/2002; 02-0919-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    President John Hennessy welcomed new students and their families to Stanford during this formal inauguration of the academic year. Opening speech ( pastor); Robin 5:31; Prof. Brogmen 11:30; Deborah Costa 17:27; Hennessy 22:42; Singing 40:49
  - 2002 Convocation, Cutaways, 09/04/2002; 02-0919-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    President John Hennessy welcomed new students and their families to Stanford during this formal inauguration of the academic year.
  - Julie Lythcott Haims, Interview, New Student Orientation, 09/10/2002; 02-0919-3; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Julie Lythcott-Haims, recently named to the post of dean of freshmen and transfer students, explained how Stanford welcomes students by memorizing their names and hometowns before they arrive on campus. She also talked about convocation.
  - Welcome Freshmen, Class of 2006, 09/19/2002; 02-0919-4; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Campus Gives Rousing Welcome to Class of 2006 STUDENTS MOVING IN; Interview with Mike, Lynne, and Rachel Cordova 4:17 ( new student); KEMIT THE LAG 5:19; Roble hall 8:17; Robin 11:50; Robin in the wig 18:15
  - SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory, B-Roll, Master, 09/20/2002; 02-0920-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:09:44
    B-roll Starts 2:31 SLAC Sign 2:40; Aerial View of SLAC 2:42; Ground shot accelerator gallery 3:48; Accelerator interiors 4:18; Testing BaBar Detector Electronics 5:10; BaBar detector 6:04; Low angle shot of BaBar 7:04
  - SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory, B-Roll, 09/20/2002; 02-0920-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:09:20
  - Dr. Chaitan Khosla, Celiac Disease, 09/20/2002; 02-0920-3; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    A team of investigators at Stanford lead by Chaitan Khosla, professor of chemistry, chemical engineering and biochemistry, have discovered the cause and a potential treatment for celiac sprue, an autoimmune disease that leads to an inability to digest gluten, a major protein in wheat, rye and barley products. Slide Show: Chemistry and Biology of Celiac Sprue; All slides 3:00; Explains what Celiac Sprue is 3:50; Close up of the vera 5:50; Child with C.S. picture 9:48; Interview 11:41
  - Footage of Students, B-Roll, 09/30/2002; 02-0930-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Students on bikes Family walking 2:19; Students coming out of class 10:00; Quad row 10:40; Student w/ Stanford sweatshirt 16:09; Coming out of class 25:38
  - Students at the bell tower, B-Roll, 10/01/2002; 02-1001-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Bell Tower Students on bikes; Bell Audio 1:05; Man in a wheelchair with Stanford and American Flags 4:52; Students studying under the bell 5:40; Students on 7:14 ( Compression); Students at the bike racks 9:39; Students with friends 10:39
  - Andy Krackow's Party, Olive's Cafe, 10/03/2002; 02-1003-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Going away party for Andy Krackow, web managing editor. Grand Opening of Olives Cafe, it opened that week. Olives (its official title is Olives@Building 160) is the second retail café opened by Dining Services.
  - Hoover and Clock Tower with students, B-Roll, 10/08/2002; 02-1008-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Fountain pan up to tower :30:00 Water Bubble 2:20:00; Memorial Auto. 3:30:00; Hoover and Light poles 3:38:00; Tight shot of Hoover and lightpole 5:10; Hoover and light pull 5:50:00; Hoover and light push 6:20:00; Students on bikes 7:20:00; Students on bikes wide 9:11; Columns 12:20; Student with friends 14:10:00; Clock 15:02
  - Musical Tribute to Daniel Pearl, 10/10/2002; 02-1010-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Pianist and music Assistant Professor Mark Applebaum and the St. Lawrence String Quartet performed a tribute to Daniel Pearl '85, a journalist who was murdered in Pakistan last year. His sister, Michelle Pearl '91, attended the concert held in Memorial Church
  - Musical Tribute to Daniel Pearl, Master, 10/10/2002; 02-1010-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:57:52
    Pianist and music Assistant Professor Mark Applebaum and the St. Lawrence String Quartet performed a tribute to Daniel Pearl '85, a journalist who was murdered in Pakistan last year. His sister, Michelle Pearl '91, attended the concert held in Memorial Church.
  - Musical Tribute to Daniel Pearl, 10/10/2002; 02-1010-3; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
  - Mini DV Archives, Cutaways, 10/16/2002; 02-1016-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Cutaways from previous projects.
  - Wallenberg Hall Dedication, 10/24/2001; 02-1024-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Dedication of Wallenberg Hall, formerly Building 160. The Knut and Alice Wallenberg Foundation and the Marianne and Marcus Wallenberg Foundation of Sweden made a $15 million grant to the university in 1999. Part of the funding was used to renovate Building 160, and part supports projects that explore the use of technology in education.
  - Wallenberg Hall Dedication, 10/24/2001; 02-1024-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:20:00
  - Alexandria Boehm, Beach Closures, Santa Cruz, 11/01/2002; 02-1101-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Assistant Professor Alexandria Boehm talks about how pollution events at beaches often last just one day or one hour, so the problem is likely to have passed by the time a warning sign is posted. Boehm also explains how sunlight and full moons can influence the decision to close beaches.
  - Mechanical Engineering, Car Engines, Computers, 11/08/2002; 02-1108-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Students and Instructors working on the car 1:27 Inside the car 2:04; Man gets in the car 2:30; Turning the steering wheel 2:50; Front view of the car 3:00; Student aid lectures about the engine 3:15; Wide shot of students 4:25; Pointing at the engine 4:30; Students 5:19; Teacher 6:21; Corvette engine 10:55; Putting the engine together 12:33 - 14:48; Taking the engine apart 16:00 -27:00; Computers 28:00
  - Packard Electrical Engineering Building, Sequoia Hall B-Roll, 11/11/2002; 02-1111-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 5:41
    B-Roll shots of Packard Electrical Engineering Building and Sequoia Hall Packard Sign 0:4:00; Left pan of Packard :31:00; Wide of Packard :53:00; Wide of both Packard and Sequoia 1:40; Sequoia Hall 3:25; Fountain 3:32
  - Mechanical Engineering, B-Roll, 11/11/2002; 02-1111-3; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    B-Roll footage of engineering students working in computer labs.
  - Global Climate and Energy Project (GCEP) Project Video News Release, Audio Track, 11/12/2002; 02-1112-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Voice over for the Global Climate and Energy Project (GCEP) project Video News Release by Jack Hubbard.
  - Hennessy, Emergency Drill Press Conference, 11/13/2002; 02-1113-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 15:43
    Press Conference about Emergency Drill conducted by the Emergency Operations Center. It was a mock 7.2 earthquake and the aftermath 36 hours on.
  - Global Climate and Energy Project VNR, No Slates, 11/14/2002; 02-1114-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:03:27
    President John Hennessy and G-CEP Director Lynn Orr discuss Stanford's role in the Global Climate and Energy Project. (No Slates)
  - SIEPR Exteriors, CREDPR Office, B-Roll, 11/14/2002; 02-1114-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 4:45
    SIEPR and Hoover; Car passes through shot :59:00 / 1:40; Person walks through shot 1:56 / 2:09; Sign 2:38; Helen on the phone 3:20; "good morning.." 3:42 / 3:54; Sign 4:30
  - Global Climate and Energy Project Announcement, Video News Release, 11/20/2002; 02-1120-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Video news release: Stanford announces the Global Climate and Energy Project. It is to conduct fundamental research on technologies that will permit the development of global energy systems with significantly lower greenhouse gas emissions.
  - Jasper Ridge Plots, Chris Field, Nona Chiarello, Becky Shaw, 11/26/2002; 02-1126-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Jasper Ridge Global Change Project, a 3 year experiment, is testing plots of land. The plots are given high levels of water, heat, carbon dioxide and nitrogen in different combinations to simulate predicted global climate change in the next hundred years. Interviews with Stanford researcher Nona Chiarello, Stanford Professor Christopher Field, and Nature Conservancy scientist Rebecca Shaw
  - Stem Cell Institute Clips, 12/10/2002; 02-1210-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Newly created Institute for Stem Cell Biology and Regenerative Medicine clips of the institute.
  - Stanford Night Campus Shots, Bumpers, 12/11/2002; 02-1211-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Stanford Night Shot Bumpers. These are short shots of various locations used for transitions.
  - Terman Biochemical Engineering Lab, A. Spormann, (3), 11/12/2002; 02-1211-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    B-Roll of Terman Bio-Chemical engineering labs, labs and test tubes and Professor Alfred Spormann. [This b-roll is believed to have been used with the GCEP announcement.]
  - Hoover Tower, B-Roll, 01/00/2003; 03-0100-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:00:34
    Campus B-Roll includes fountain, tower, pond, and waterfall.
  - Stanford Night Campus Shots, Bumpers (2), 01/07/2003; 03-0107-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Stanford Night Shot Bumpers. These are short shots of various locations used for transitions. Hoover, Main Quad.
  - Steve Palumbi, Marine Reserves, Interview, 01/09/2003; 03-0109-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 10:00
    Biological sciences Professor Stephen R. Palumbi discussed the need to protect America's oceans and marine reserves
  - Mini DV Archives, Reel #1, 01/14/2003; 03-0114-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    0000000 - 0003228 Student rally against the war in Iraq 0003705 -0014712 Jose Bedia; 0015004 - 0031222 William Perry; 0031222 - 0053001 Christy Smith; 0053001 - 0061205 Nicole Nicholas (tap); 0061205 - 0080216 Candles for Columbia; 0081522 - 0094924 David Dill ------------------------------------------Timecode Break---------------------------------------- 0000000 - 0015329 Phillip Prodger; 0015329 - 0040702 Tractor GPS; 0040702 - 0072813 Mock Trail; 0074203 - 0091006 John Gabreili; 0091006 - 0111915 Beligian Royals; 0111915 - 0120206 Anti war protest (nationwide); 0120728 - 0141705 Robots ------------------------------------------Timecode Break---------------------------------------- 0000801 - 0024527 Lawrence Wein; 0024527 - 0043619 Elephant; 0043619 - 0061301 Hapics; 0062027 - 0081619 Take your kids to work day
  - Lawrence Wein, Anthrax Defense, 01/14/2003; 03-0114-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Lawrence Wein of Stanford University's Graduate School of Business discusses a study published the week of March 17 in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences (PNAS). The study suggests that a reasonable defense against an airborne anthrax attack requires more aggressive action by the U.S. government than now planned.
  - Marine Reserves, Presser, Stanford Law School, 01/14/2003; 03-0114-3a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Former White House Chief of Staff Leon Panetta and biological sciences Professor Stephen R. Palumbi discussed the need to protect America's oceans at a press conference at the Stanford Law School Jan. 14. Kathleen Sullivan 0:00:48:16 -0:05:31:11; B-roll time:(0:19:44:01-0:20:27:22 ); Leon Panetta 0:05:31:11 - 0:22:08:22; Stephen Palumbi 0:22:08:22 - 0:33:20:00
  - Marine Reserves, Presser, Stanford Law School, 01/14/2003; 03-0114-3b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Former White House Chief of Staff Leon Panetta and biological sciences Professor Stephen R. Palumbi discussed the need to protect America's oceans at a press conference at the Stanford Law School Jan. 14.
  - José Bedia, Exhibit: Nsila-El Camino: José Bedia and the Spirit's Path in Congo Art, 01/15/2003; 03-0115-1a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    José Bedia, 44, discusses a painting in his exhibition, Nsila-El Camino: José Bedia and the Spirit's Path in Congo Art, and how it relates to the overall theme of the show. The painting was one element of a larger installation he created in the gallery Jan. 15, the opening day of the exhibition. interview begins 4:24:12; B-roll Time 4:33:00
  - José Bedia, Exhibit: Nsila-El Camino: José Bedia and the Spirit's Path in Congo Art, 01/15/2003; 03-0115-1b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    José Bedia, 44, discusses a painting in his exhibition, Nsila-El Camino: José Bedia and the Spirit's Path in Congo Art, and how it relates to the overall theme of the show. The painting was one element of a larger installation he created in the gallery Jan. 15, the opening day of the exhibition. Complete B-roll
  - William Perry, SIEPR, North Korea, 01/15/2003; 03-0115-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 1:08:00
    China is in a unique position to defuse the mounting nuclear brinkmanship on the Korean Peninsula, Professor William J. Perry, former secretary of defense, told associates of the Stanford Institute for Economic Policy Research.
  - Anti War Demonstration, 01/16/2003; 03-0116-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:10:10
    Anti war demonstration About 400 Student rally against the war in Iraq
  - Cactus Garden, Christy Smith, 01/17/2003; 03-0117-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Christy Smith, Arizona Garden volunteer coordinator, discusses the restoration and planting scheme for the 1880s cactus garden that was originally planted for Jane and Leland Stanford. Christy Smith 8:53:00; garden tour and facts about the garden series of shots 12:16
  - Bob Beyers Funeral, 01/26/2003; 03-0126-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Funeral services for Robert W. Beyers, Former Stanford News Service director. In 1983, Beyers became the third person to receive the Kenneth M. Cuthbertson Award, Stanford's highest honor for exceptional service to the university.
  - Hopkins Marine Station, Mark Denny, Steve Palumbi, 01/27/2003; 03-0127-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Professors Mark Denny and Steve Palumbi of Stanford's Hopkins Marine Station describe the coastal "neighborhoods" that live along the shoreline. Denny discusses research on the effect of ocean waves on small marine organisms, and Palumbi describes new studies on marine genetics.
  - Nicole Nicolas, Tap Dancer, 01/31/2003; 03-0131-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Undergraduate Nicole Nicholas, granddaughter of tap legend Fayard Nicholas, led a free master class for beginning and intermediate tap dancers Jan. 31 in Roble Dance Studio.
  - David Dill, Electronic Voting Machines, 02/03/2003; 03-0203-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:11:01
    Computer scientists from around the country, led by Professor David Dill, say computerized voting machines should provide a voter-verifiable audit trail.
  - Columbia Astronaut Prayer Vigil, Memorial Church, 02/03/2003; 03-0203-2; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    A prayer vigil commemorating the lives of the seven astronauts lost on the space shuttle Columbia was held Monday, Feb. 3, 2003, from noon to 12:20 p.m. in Memorial Church. William "Scotty" McLennan and Patricia Karlin-Neumann, deans for religious life, presided. On Saturday, Feb. 1, Columbia broke up over Texas during its descent to earth. The seven astronauts on board were lost.
  - Philip Prodger, Time Stands Still: Muybridge and the Instantaneous Photography Movement, Cantor Art Museum, 02/05/2003; 03-0205-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 34:00
    Phillip Prodger, curator of "Time Stands Still: Muybridge and the Instantaneous Photography Movement," discusses the context of Eadweard Muybridge's photography. The exhibit will remain on view through May 11 at the Cantor Center for Visual Arts. cut aways begin: 07:42:00
  - John Gabrieli, Dyslexics, 02/21/2003; 03-0221-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Professor John Gabrieli discusses how the brains of dyslexic children, after undergoing intensive training, can be rewired to function more like those found in normal readers.
  - Belgian Royalty visit campus, 02/24/2003; 03-0224-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Length: 00:02:01
    Crown Prince Philippe and Princess Matilda of Belgium visited Stanford and the Hoover Institution Feb. 24. The visit was an homage to the Hoover Institution, which has had close ties to Belgium since World War I when the former president launched an aid program. It also was a trip down memory lane for the prince, who earned a master's degree in political science from Stanford in 1985. The royals toured the campus, visited Hoover Tower and Carillon, and met 30 Belgian students at the Bechtel International Center.
  - Belgian Royalty visit campus, 02/24/2003; 03-0224-2a; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Crown Prince Philippe and Princess Matilda of Belgium visited Stanford and the Hoover Institution Feb. 24. The visit was an homage to the Hoover Institution, which has had close ties to Belgium since World War I when the former president launched an aid program. It also was a trip down memory lane for the prince, who earned a master's degree in political science from Stanford in 1985. The royals toured the campus, visited Hoover Tower and Carillon, and met 30 Belgian students at the Bechtel International Center. The arrival of the Belgium royalty and their tour of the campus.
  - Belgian Royalty visit campus, 02/24/2003; 03-0224-2b; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Crown Prince Philippe and Princess Matilda of Belgium visited Stanford and the Hoover Institution Feb. 24. The visit was an homage to the Hoover Institution, which has had close ties to Belgium since World War I when the former president launched an aid program. It also was a trip down memory lane for the prince, who earned a master's degree in political science from Stanford in 1985. The royals toured the campus, visited Hoover Tower and Carillon, and met 30 Belgian students at the Bechtel International Center. The Hoover visit and speech by Prince Philippe.
  - Anti-War Protest, Iraq, 03/05/2003; 03-0305-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Student take part in a nationwide protest by students all over the world, on the war in Iraq.
  - Cockroach Robots, Jonathan Clark, Trey McClung, 03/10/2003; 03-0310-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Graduate students Jonathan Clark and Trey McClung discuss how the robot model that imitates the moves of a cockroach might play a major role in earthquake and disaster rescues in the future.
  - Lawrence Wein, Press conference, Anthrax, 03/17/2003; 03-0317-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)
    Lawrence Wein of Stanford University's Graduate School of Business held a press conference about anthrax and how a reasonable defense against an airborne anthrax attack requires more aggressive action by the U.S. government than now planned.
  - Anti Iraq War Demonstration, Rush Rehm, 03/20/2003; 03-0320-1; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 11)